Christopher Olcheski

chrisolcheski@gmail.com



**** (570) 472 4659



https://www.linkedin.com/in/colcheski/



https://www.chrisolcheski.com/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with 6+ years of experience developing and maintaining web applications. In this time I have demonstrated an ability to both self start and collaborate with team members to deliver the best results possible. While leading development on an administrative and customer service tool for USPS, I have trained and onboarded multiple developers as well as continued my own development as a leader, developer, and person. I am eager to obtain a challenging new position to continue my growth and expand my knowledge while building upon my skill set in software development.

Experience

Computer Systems Developer, Sr

United States Postal Service

Feb 2016 - Present

- Led development and maintenance on an administration and customer service tool
- Automated batch jobs handling administrative tasks
- Created web tools using Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and Bootstrap
- Trained and onboarded new developers
- Promoted to mid-level developer in first year, senior in fifth year

Production Coordinator

TMG Health

Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

Utilized SQL and Macro Programs to automate report generation and claims processing

Education

Penn State University

Bachelor of Science, Information Sciences and Technology 2013 - 2015

Luzerne County Community College

Associate of Science, Computer Information Systems 2011 - 2013

Skills

- Java EE and SE
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap

- Jenkins
- Java Persistence API (JPA)
- Oracle SQL
- WebSphere Application Server
- Apache ANT and Maven
- Gradle

- Sonar
- Subversion
- GIT
- VersionOne
- Unix CLI
- .NET